=Yes, Her Majesty=
= نعم صاحبة الجلالة =
=Episode 1=
= الحلقة 1 =
Your Majesty, there are a lot of people here.
جلالة الملك ، هناك الكثير من الناس هنا.
We should go back.
يجب أن نعود.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
the palace gate will be closed in an hour.
ستغلق بوابة القصر خلال ساعة.
All right.
حسنًا.
Ruo Lan.
رو لان.
Your Majesty, my name is Lan Ruo.
جلالة الملك ، اسمي لان رو.
Lan Ruo.
لان رو.
Did I fall into this river?
هل وقعت في هذا النهر؟
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.
Xin An.
شين آن.
Your Majesty, my name is An Xin.
جلالة الملك ، اسمي آن شين.
An Xin.
أن شين.
How long have I been fainted after I fell into the river?
منذ متى وأنا أغمي علي بعد أن سقطت في النهر؟
Your Majesty, around three days.
جلالة الملك ، حوالي ثلاثة أيام.
Look at that gentleman!
انظر إلى ذلك الرجل!
Yes.
نعم.
Who is that?
من ذاك؟
He looks so handsome.
إنه يبدو وسيمًا جدًا.
Your Majesty, he's your beloved in this life.
جلالة الملك ، هو حبيبك في هذه الحياة.
There's nobody that can compare...
لا يوجد أحد يمكنه المقارنة ...
Your Empress.
إمبراطورة الخاص بك.
Li Shihao.
لي شيهاو.
My Empress, Li Shihao?
إمبراطورة بلدي ، لي شيهاو؟
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
=Yes, Her Majesty=
= نعم صاحبة الجلالة =
(Imperial Study)
(دراسة إمبراطورية)
Your Majesty, you should take a rest.
جلالة الملك ، يجب أن تأخذ قسطا من الراحة.
You have yet to recover from falling into the river.
لا يزال يتعين عليك التعافي من السقوط في النهر.
You've been reading memorials for four hours.
لقد كنت تقرأ النصب التذكارية لمدة أربع ساعات.
(I fell into the river three days ago)
(سقطت في النهر قبل ثلاثة أيام)
(and I was unconscious.)
(وكنت فاقدًا للوعي).
(I woke up yesterday and I've lost all my memory.)
(استيقظت أمس وفقدت كل ذاكرتي).
(They said I'm the Emperor of Great Yan, Yue Lizheng.)
(قالوا إنني إمبراطور يان العظيمة ، يو ليزينج.)
(I've accepted the setting)
(لقد قبلت الإعداد)
(after a while.)
(بعد حين.)
(After all, being the Emperor)
(بعد كل شيء ، كونه الإمبراطور)
(is like my specialty.)
(مثل تخصصي).
(It's a shame that my Empress, Li Shihao,)
(من العار أن تكون إمبراطوريتي ، لي شيهاو ،)
(is a beauty when he doesn't speak.)
(هو جمال عندما لا يتكلم).
(But when he speaks...)
(ولكن عندما يتكلم ...)
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
(He doesn't look smart.)
(لا يبدو ذكيًا).
(He's really not my favourite.)
(إنه حقًا ليس المفضل لدي.)
Your Majesty, it's time to choose your companion tonight.
جلالة الملك ، حان الوقت لاختيار رفيقك الليلة.
I didn't know that I have so many husbands in the harem.
لم أكن أعرف أن لدي الكثير من الأزواج في الحريم.
(Slash, Stroke, Zag, Horizontal.)
(مائل ، شوط ، زاغ ، أفقي.)
(Slash, Stroke.)
(القطع ، السكتة الدماغية.)
(Stroke, Zag.)
(السكتة الدماغية ، المنشار)
(Zag, Horizontal.)
(زاغ ، أفقي.)
Was I uneducated before fainted?
هل كنت غير متعلم قبل أن أغمي علي؟
(Slash, Stroke, Zag, Horizontal.) I only used a radical
(Slash، Stroke، Zag، Horizontal.) لقد استخدمت فقط جذريًا
to name them?
(Slash، Stroke، Zag، Horizontal.) لتسميتها؟
I'll meet Mr. Slash tonight.
سوف أقابل السيد سلاش الليلة.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.
Mr. Slash.
السيد سلاش.
Mr. Slash is indeed majestic
السيد سلاش مهيب بالفعل
and well-mannered.
وحسن الخلق.
Thank you for your compliment, Your Majesty.
أشكرك على إطرائك يا جلالة الملك.
Empress?
إمبراطورة؟
How come it's you?
كيف هذا انت
I've made a mistake.
لقد ارتكبت خطأ.
Do it again.
افعلها مرة أخرى.
Mr. Stroke.
السيد ستروك.
Mr. Stroke is a gentleman.
السيد ستروك رجل نبيل.
It's indeed true.
هذا صحيح بالفعل.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
How come it's you again?
كيف تعال أنت مرة أخرى؟
I don't believe this.
لا أصدق هذا.
Am I in a maze?
هل أنا في متاهة؟
Do it again.
افعلها مرة أخرى.
Mr. Zag.
السيد زاغ.
Are you the Empress?
هل انت الامبراطورة
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
how did you know it's me?
كيف عرفت انه انا
There's only you alone in my harem?
هل يوجد أنت وحدك في حريمى؟
Yes.
نعم.
Your Majesty and I are getting along.
جلالة الملك وأنا نتفق.
You'll never take in another concubine.
لن تأخذ أبدا في محظية أخرى.
What about the tablet An Xin
ماذا عن الجهاز اللوحي An Xin
was holding?
كان يمسك؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
read all the radicals together.
قراءة كل المتطرفين معا.
Slash, stroke, zag, horizontal.
الخط المائل ، السكتة الدماغية ، الزاج ، أفقي.
(Empress) Empress?
(الإمبراطورة) إمبراطورة؟
That's right.
صحيح.
You...
أنت...
Empress,
الإمبراطورة
it's getting late.
الوقت يتأخر.
You should go back and take a rest.
يجب أن تعود وتأخذ قسطا من الراحة.
I...
أنا...
Your Majesty, do you dislike me?
جلالة الملك ، هل تكرهني؟
Empress, you've been taking care of me and you must be tired.
إمبراطورة ، لقد كنت تهتم بي ويجب أن تكون متعبًا.
I'm doing this for your own good.
أنا أفعل هذا لمصلحتك.
Your Majesty, you're kind to me.
جلالة الملك ، أنت لطيف معي.
I'm leaving now.
انا راحل الان.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
My head hurts.
رأسي يؤلمني.
The imperial physician said
قال الطبيب الإمبراطوري
this is the sequelae
هذه هي العواقب
of saving Your Majesty in the river.
لإنقاذ جلالتك في النهر.
You saved me?
قمت بحفظه لي؟
I was resting in the room that day.
كنت أرتاح في الغرفة في ذلك اليوم.
When I heard that Your Majesty fell into the river,
عندما سمعت أن جلالتك سقطت في النهر
I rushed there like a loosen horse
هرعت إلى هناك مثل حصان رخو
and jumped into the river like a green dragon.
وقفز في النهر مثل تنين أخضر.
You can see the waves.
تستطيع أن ترى الأمواج.
I saved Your Majesty.
لقد أنقذت جلالتك.
My head hurts.
رأسي يؤلمني.
Feel it.
اشعر بها.
Am I having a fever?
هل أعاني من الحمى؟
Empress.
الإمبراطورة.
It's in the middle of summer.
إنه في منتصف الصيف.
You're wearing too many clothes.
أنت ترتدي الكثير من الملابس.
Your Majesty, please help me to take them off.
جلالة الملك ، الرجاء مساعدتي في خلعهم.
(I think I smelled this)
(أعتقد أنني شممت هذه الرائحة)
(before I fell into the river,)
(قبل أن أسقط في النهر)
(but he said)
(لكنه قال)
(he only arrived after I fell into the river.)
(وصل فقط بعد أن سقطت في النهر).
The night is beautiful.
الليل جميل.
Let me serve Your Majesty in bed.
دعني أخدم جلالتك في السرير.
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Your Highness, you finished it so quickly?
صاحب السمو ، هل انتهيت من ذلك بسرعة؟
Is there a special scent on my body?
هل هناك رائحة خاصة على جسدي؟
Smell of the fragrance...
رائحة العطر ...
And?
و؟
Sweat.
يعرق.
A man's smell.
رائحة الرجل.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
You're getting more and more ridiculous.
أنت تزداد سخافة أكثر فأكثر.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Why did the Empress save me the other day?
لماذا أنقذتني الإمبراطورة ذلك اليوم؟
As soon Your Majesty fell into the river,
حالما سقط جلالتك في النهر ،
His Highness rushed there as quick as he could.
هرع سموه إلى هناك بأسرع ما يمكن.
He rushed there like a loosen horse
هرع إلى هناك مثل حصان رخو
and jumped into the lake like a green dragon.
وقفز في البحيرة مثل التنين الأخضر.
You can see the waves everywhere and he saved Your Majesty.
يمكنك أن ترى الأمواج في كل مكان وقد أنقذ جلالتك.
(It's the same as what the Empress said.)
(إنه نفس ما قالته الإمبراطورة).
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Why did the Empress save me?
لماذا أنقذتني الإمبراطورة؟
His Highness
صاحب السمو
rushed there like a loosen horse.
اندفع هناك مثل حصان رخو.
Enough.
كافٍ.
You tell me.
أخبرني أنت.
Are you all bought off by the Empress?
هل تم شراء جميعكم من قبل الإمبراطورة؟
If I ever speak lies, let the thunder...
إذا تحدثت بالكذب ، دع الرعد ...
How dare you quibble?
كيف تجرؤ على المراوغة؟
Your Majesty, please forgive me.
جلالة الملك ، أرجوك سامحني.
The thunder strikes me not because I'm telling lies.
لا يضربني الرعد لأنني أكذب.
It's because
انه بسبب
I'm born with a jinxed mouth.
أنا ولدت بفم ضعيف.
If Your Majesty doesn't believe me,
إذا جلالتك لا تصدقني ،
let the thunder...
دع الرعد ...
Something bad happened!
شيء ما سيء حدث!
Your Majesty's bedroom has been struck and is on fire now!
غرفة نوم جلالتك تعرضت للقصف واشتعلت فيها النيران الآن!
Your Majesty...
جلالة الملك ...
Shut up!
اسكت!
Hurry up!
أسرع - بسرعة!
- Hurry up! - Water!
- أسرع - بسرعة!  - ماء!
This way!
من هنا!
Water! Take the water here!
ماء!  خذ الماء هنا!
(It's been three days since I fell into the river.)
(لقد مرت ثلاثة أيام منذ أن سقطت في النهر).
(When they talk about how the Empress saved me,)
(عندما يتحدثون عن كيف أنقذتني الإمبراطورة ،)
(they were like acting in collusion.)
(كانوا مثل العمل بالتواطؤ).
(The Empress said he was resting when I fell into the river,)
(قالت الإمبراطورة إنه كان يرتاح عندما سقطت في النهر ،)
(but obviously I smelled the scent)
(لكن من الواضح أنني شممت الرائحة)
(on his body before I fell.)
(على جسده قبل أن أسقط).
(Is he trying to cover up something?)
(هل يحاول التستر على شيء ما؟)
Hurry up!
أسرع - بسرعة!
I've only left for a while.
لقد غادرت فقط لفترة من الوقت.
Why would Her Majesty's bedroom be on fire?
لماذا تحترق غرفة نوم صاحبة الجلالة؟
Hurry up!
أسرع - بسرعة!
The water is not enough! Hurry up!
الماء لا يكفي!  أسرع - بسرعة!
Your Majesty, be careful!
جلالة الملك ، كن حذرا!
(Could it be the person who caused me to fall)
(هل يمكن أن يكون الشخص هو الذي تسبب لي في السقوط)
(was the Empress?)
(هل كانت الإمبراطورة؟)
♪Even though it's hard to say goodbye♪
♪ رغم أنه من الصعب أن نقول وداعًا
♪We're nothing compared to the world♪
♪ نحن لا شيء مقارنة بالعالم ♪
♪Holding deep grudges♪
يحمل ضغائن عميقة ♪
♪But flowers blossom late♪
♪ لكن الزهور تتفتح متأخرة ♪
♪Asking why we need to be apart♪
يسأل لماذا يجب أن نفترق ♪
♪Waiting from new moon to full moon♪
♪ الانتظار من القمر الجديد إلى اكتمال القمر
♪Vow becomes poem♪
نذر يصبح قصيدة ♪
♪But I dare not read it♪
♪ لكنني لا أجرؤ على قراءتها ♪
♪Even though it's hard to say goodbye♪
♪ رغم أنه من الصعب أن نقول وداعًا
♪We're nothing compared to the world♪
♪ نحن لا شيء مقارنة بالعالم ♪
♪Holding deep grudges♪
يحمل ضغائن عميقة ♪
♪But flowers blossom late♪
♪ لكن الزهور تتفتح متأخرة ♪